Thank you, Lane. Asalaamu Alaikum. Shalom. Waap'pain. Pazu D'Iwario. Ventre.
And what's the Indian? Shunai. Shunai from India.
And any other language that I forgot, I'll meet it for you later on this
evening. I want to first as always thank the creator of the universe, who we
know by many names I've referred to God as Allah.
And we know that the name of God is a linguistic terminology that always means
the most high. The creator who has brought us all up a state of non-existence
and given us life, and given us spirits, and given us souls, and given us minds,
and given us more inside of ourselves than we see outside of ourselves.
And we're eternally grateful to the creator for not just giving us lives, but
also giving us guidance through all the various scriptures and all the heroes
and sheroes that brought inspiration to humanity all over the world about the
importance of spirituality, about the importance of self and power.
And I would be remissive and acknowledge and bear witness to those whose
shoulders that I stand on, who paid a mighty price for us to be here today. I
am a descendant of First Nation people on my father's side who were Cherokee,
who were brought here on the left side of the mountains, as they say, from the
rocky side over to the flat side of Tennessee and Alaska.
And my great grandfather was one of the great slaves who was descendants of the
Gambian cynical reasons of Africa. And I thank Almighty God for being a
descendant of them and being able to understand and acknowledge my ancestors in
the way that so many African Americans have not been able to.
And so I bear witness to this struggle. They didn't come here by way of the Mayflower.
They didn't come here by way of Ellis Island. They came here in the halls of
slave ship. And we should always recognize and understand the importance of
that travel from the west coast of Africa to the east coast of America and that
sojourn here in North America.
So we understand the brilliance of the diversity of this country, but also the
brilliance of what we call the resilience of all of our people who have
practiced history and thank Almighty God for them. And thank you for being here
tonight.
I want to give a big shout out to the Hanson family, who has really been, I can't
even imagine where we would be without the ambassadors of this international
gathering at the Soul Corps.
And may we continue to acknowledge their work and may they continue to do work
that they're doing to great gatherings like this that where we celebrate
diversity and celebrate ourselves as ethnic Americans in this family park
called America.
And I also want to say I will be reduced to the Valley of the College and
recognize the city itself and these great guys that are here this evening that
also represent the importance of unity and diversity.
Not just not uniformity, but uniformity in the fact that they got the sinners
of those who came here and struggled and made a life for themselves and
celebrate themselves as well.
It's very important that we celebrate diversity and understand the importance
of this struggle. I also want to say that it's important for these kinds of
events to take place because Cleveland is a pivotal city.
Obviously in the next couple of months the whole world will be looking at us
and all of us are ambassadors and we continue to be ambassadors even not into
the Republican National Convention, but also afterwards because a lot of eyes
will be on Cleveland.
And I know that we want to make sure that we shine not just for the city, but
for what we represent as those involved in this diversity issue.
My grandmother used to say there are people who make things happen, there are
people who watch things happen, and there are some people who say what happened.
I don't want you to be that group.
She always encouraged me to make sure that I made something happen in life for
myself and make sure that I try to make a difference in the lives of other
people.
My grandmother came here as I said before. Her mother was a full-blooded
Cherokee and she was from Pulaski.
And if you're not familiar with Pulaski, Pulaski was the birthplace of the Ku
Klux Klan. So here we've got our Pulaski and came to Cleveland.
But she became an entrepreneur and she sold magazines and books and newspapers
from various cities throughout the United States that were from the black press,
from Baltimore, from Detroit, from St. Louis and all these different places.
But she also sold the plane dealer and I would have to come here early in the
morning before sunrise to help put these papers together so she could sell that
plane dealer.
And I would sit there and read all these other newspapers from other cities
throughout the United States.
And I saw that there was so much commonality in various things that were going
on throughout urban America and the United States.
And that is what inspired me to find out more about my roots. I began to read
books about classical African civilization.
I began to read books about the Moors that had lived in Spain and helped civilize
possibly even when there was no understanding of who the Moors were.
But we know now that we hear about cities like Toledo, we hear about places
like Cordova, which is not just a car, it's a city.
There's a city down the street called Medina. A lot of people don't remember it.
It used to be called Medina at one time.
So we began to associate things with language by picking up on all of these
markers of linguistic similarity and then we can understand why it's important
to celebrate ourselves.
So I chose the name Callebso Mod for myself after studying what the name is and
then began to try to make things happen.
And for the last 40 years, as a result of my family and friends and the support
group that I have here, we've been able to do many things.
But we want to do more. And one of the most important things that we want to do
is to show young men and women in general, but African Americans in particular,
that they can transform themselves.
They can visualize a future for themselves. If they can visualize it and
believe it, then their willpower will allow them to achieve it.
And it's important that we continue to ring that bell in their minds about
transformation because everybody's got a tuning fork.
Everybody's got a tuning fork. And many of the people in the population that we
work with, they've covered their work up with a lot of other things.
There's a lot of trauma in our communities. There's a lot of mental health,
social health. There's a lot of economic, unhealthy economic communities.
And so what we need to do, what we have to do, is to go and cut through all of
that and show them that the tuning fork that can be here can ignite them to go
through a transformation process like the caterpillar to the butterfly.
That caterpillar goes into cocoon and uses its own body in order to make that
cocoon. And then out of that comes a butterfly.
That to me is a very beautiful picture of transformation of what can happen.
And let's continue to work on that.
I will continue to work with people like Dan and everybody. We see so many
familiar faces.
I remember Dan Coughlin when I was a young man playing basketball. He said,
back in the day, we were playing dealer and a lot of the Dick Russ and a lot of
the long ground.
And we worked not just in the hood, so to speak, even though we do a lot of
work in the hood.
It's important we understand we're global people and that we're just as
comfortable in a sloppy village as we are in Little Italy, as we are in Polastan,
as we are in the African American communities, as we are in the Asian Plaza.
And as we continue to focus on what we have in common with each other, then I
think we can be successful not only in this mic, but also in the next.
Thank you very much. I love you. And let's thank you for our rest of the tuning
work.
[APPLAUSE]